<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Page on Valerio Francescangeli</title><link>https://v19i.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home Page on Valerio Francescangeli</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</managingEditor><webMaster>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 10:40:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v19i.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GraphQL: Publish the Schema of Your Company, Not Your Api</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/graphql-publish-the-schema-of-your-company-not-your-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 10:40:08 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/graphql-publish-the-schema-of-your-company-not-your-api/</guid><description>GraphQL: Publish the Schema of Your Company, Not Your Api GraphQL is an interesting technology that promises better developer and user experience, but its usefulness can be misinterpreted as an overall better technology than what came before it.
To best utilise it, a specific organisation approach must be used. GraphQL works best when the whole organisation shares the same domain conventions. Domain Driven Design shines in a GraphQL environment, but it requires a lot of effort to change a company’s mentality and embrace it.</description></item><item><title>A More Consistent Future for the Web</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/a-more-consistent-future-for-the-web/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 14:42:51 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/a-more-consistent-future-for-the-web/</guid><description>A More Consistent Future for the Web Last week at Google I/O 2023, a new initiative was presented: the Web Platform Baseline.
What is it? It is a multi-company effort from the newly formed Web Developer Experience Group, also known as the WebDX Community Group, that wants to improve the developer experience by providing a unified set of same-to-use features.
Any feature in the Baseline is guaranteed to work without critical bugs in all major browsers’ previous and current versions: Chrome, Edge, Firefox and Safari.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Technical Tests in the Software Industry</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/exploring-technical-tests-in-the-software-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:04:15 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/exploring-technical-tests-in-the-software-industry/</guid><description>Exploring Technical Tests in the Software Industry Technical tests are a staple of the tech industry interview process; they are used to assess the candidate’s communication, knowledge and problem-solving skills. This article will delve into the most commonly used ones.
Take Home Assignment This type renounces on interaction and communication skills, which will have to be measured in a follow-up session, to allow for a longer time allowance to solve a problem.</description></item><item><title>On hiring software engineers</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/on-hiring-software-engineers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 13:22:00 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/on-hiring-software-engineers/</guid><description>On hiring software engineers In the past few years, the tech industry has seen a significant shift in hiring practices, with many companies attempting to replicate the FAANG method without fully understanding the context or requirements. This has led to a complicated and inefficient hiring process that often wastes both the company&amp;rsquo;s and the candidates&amp;rsquo; time.
This blog post will discuss how to create a healthy hiring process.
Creating a customised hiring process Each company has different requirements for their tech team.</description></item><item><title>Single and Multi Purposed Software</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/single-and-multi-purposed-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 09:13:11 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/single-and-multi-purposed-software/</guid><description>Single and multi-purposed software There are two types of software, the ones with a specific focus (single-purpose) and the ones with multiple functionalities (multi-purpose).
Single-purpose software Single-purpose software, also known as focused or task-oriented software, is created specifically to get a single job done. The ideal workflow allows the user to quickly open the app, complete their task and get on with their day.
Examples Currency converter Room booking Translator Video player Simple text editor (TextEdit and Notepad).</description></item><item><title>React Pattern: Compound Component</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/react-pattern-compound-component/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 13:03:35 +0000</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/react-pattern-compound-component/</guid><description>React Pattern: Compound Component When creating custom UI components in React, an easy to evolve and implement solution is to add more props to an element to describe what to show on screen and what functions to call. It enables us to create a lot with a low level of abstraction and is usually a good choice.
One problem arises when creating a component used by a third party or another team (like in a component library).</description></item><item><title>On Test Driven Development</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/on-test-driven-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 09:27:27 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/on-test-driven-development/</guid><description>On Test-driven development Test-driven development is a technique at the basis of Agile software development and is, in my view, the most important contributing factor to creating high-quality results.
The primary goal of Test-driven development (TDD) is to force a quick feedback loop that forces you to write in small steps.
TDD imposes writing first a test for a code that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been written yet and then writing enough code to make it produce the desired output and nothing more.</description></item><item><title>Use The Platform: URL API</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/use-the-platform-url-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:23:51 +0100</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/use-the-platform-url-api/</guid><description>Use The Platform: URL API Modern web JavaScript provides an intuitive and feature-rich interface to parse, create and edit URLs info.
This page illustrates only the parts that I use the most; for the full spec, have a look at URL and URLSearchParams.
Create a URL A URL is created by instantiating a new URL instance:
const url = new URL(&amp;#34;https://v19i.com&amp;#34;); Manage search params The created object provides an easy interface to add, edit and remove search params; it behaves similarly to Map.</description></item><item><title>Lines in Four Directions by Sol Lewitt</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/lines-in-four-directions-by-sol-lewitt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:58:12 +0000</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/lines-in-four-directions-by-sol-lewitt/</guid><description> Lines In Four Directions by Sol Lewitt</description></item><item><title>On Agile software development</title><link>https://v19i.com/posts/on-agile-software-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate><author>franz899@gmail.com (Valerio Francescangeli)</author><guid>https://v19i.com/posts/on-agile-software-development/</guid><description>On Agile software development An often distorted view In the past year, I’ve run many interviews for project-manager and engineering roles. One common thing I’ve noticed is that the industry’s idea of what Agile means, is incredibly varied, going from something that is waterfall under a different name, to a style that requires specific “Agile roles” in a team.
In this post, I’ll go through what the initial idea of Agile was, and what it should be; hopefully, this will help people realise how far from the original purpose they’ve steered.</description></item></channel></rss>